<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Firas&#39; Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Firas&#39; Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Producing figures for LaTeX documents with Gnuplot</title>
      <link>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/posts/gnuplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/posts/gnuplot/</guid>
      <description>Gnuplot is a very handy tool when it comes to producing figures to be included into your work documens, be it a report, article or any of the like. It offers much capability and enough options to produce graphs that boost the quality and the presentation of your document. But, as is the case with any programming language, it takes some time and patience to learn how to actually it efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very basic introduction to Hamilton&#39;s principle</title>
      <link>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/posts/hamilton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/posts/hamilton/</guid>
      <description>When we effortlessly let go of an object, say a tennis ball for example, we instinctively know it will fall straightforwardly to the ground. such a predicition is based on our experience and daily observations. If the ball simply went up instead of falling, this would not feel right, because it was never observed before. This simple exeperience shows that nature is picky: for given circumstances, it does not behave randomly but rather seems to carefully choose one realizable outcome out of all possibilities (at least in classical mechanics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PhD Work</title>
      <link>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/posts/my-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/posts/my-phd/</guid>
      <description>Subject: Mathematical analysis and numerical simulation of dispersive models by Extended Lagrangians. Advisors: Jean-Paul Vila (PhD advisor), Nicolas Favrie (PhD co-advisor) , Sergey Gavrilyuk (Advisor) Location: This is a joint project between IMT (Toulouse) and IUSTI (Marseille). Defense: It will be held at IMT by the end of 2020 ( to be determined ).  The main motivation The main motivation of my work is to derive a first order hyperbolic system that closely approximates dispersive equations of the Euler-Korteweg type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career</title>
      <link>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/about/</guid>
      <description>Education   2017-Present -  Université Paul Sabatier-Institut de Mathématiques de Toulouse:
PhD in applied maths : Mathematical analysis and numerical simulation of dispersive models by augmented Lagrangians.  2016-2017 -  Aix-Marseille Université:
Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Multiphase Flows, Energetics and Combustion.  2013-2016 -  Ecole Nationale d&amp;rsquo;Ingénieurs de Tunis:
National Diploma of Engineering in Modelling for Industry and Services. (MIndS)  2011-2013 -  Institut Préparatoire aux Etudes d&amp;rsquo;Ingénieurs d&amp;rsquo;El Manar:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/contact/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; (+33) 05 61 55 93 07
 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp; or &amp;nbsp; 
 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; INSA de Toulouse - Département de Génie Mathématique - Office 131
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 145, avenue de Rangueil
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; 31077 Toulouse cedex 4 France</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhaouadifiras.github.io/website/publications/</guid>
      <description>Papers  Dhaouadi F, Favrie N, Gavrilyuk S. Extended Lagrangian approach for the defocusing nonlinear Schrödinger equation. Stud Appl Math. 2018;1–23.  preprint &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;  journal Dhaouadi F, Duval E, Tkachenko S,Vila J-P. Stability theory for some scalar finite difference schemes : Validity of the modified equations approach. ESAIM: Proceedings and Surveys. (Submitted)   preprint  Communications  Waves in one World Seminar -  Online at home :  Slides</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>